Have you ever read a paper that was extremely difficult to read and you wondered why it
Có bao giờ bạn đọc một bài báo mà bạn cảm thấy rất khó để đọc và bạn tự hỏi tại sao
wasn’t written in more simple sentences?
nó không được viết bởi những câu đơn giản hơn?
Sometimes research is written in a way that is needlessly complicated.
Đôi khi bài nghiên cứu được viết một cách phức tạp không cần thiết.
Often we see sentences like this “The research will allow for the provision of greater understanding
Thường ta sẽ thấy những câu như "The research will allow for the provision of greater understanding
of student preferences.”
of student preferences."
What we see here is an example of a writer replacing a verb with an Abstract noun.
Ta thấy đây là một ví dụ khi người viết thay thế động từ bằng một danh từ trừu tượng.
Now remember?
Bạn nhớ chứ?
A noun is a naming word and a verb is a doing word.
Danh từ là một từ đặt tên và động từ là từ chỉ hành động.
“the provision of” in this sentence is the Abstract noun.
"the provision of" trong câu này là danh từ trừu tượng.
The word “provision” is not a doing word or a verb.
Từ "provision" không phải là từ chỉ hành động hay một động từ.
Rewriting this sentence by changing the noun into a verb would be “The research will
Viết lại câu này bằng cách thay đổi danh từ thành động từ "The research will
provide a greater understanding of student preferences”.
provide a greater understanding of student preferences".
The word PROVIDE here is the verb.
Từ "PROVIDE" ở đây là động từ.
Rewriting the sentence this way makes the sentence sound shorter, active, and more to
Viết lại câu thế này sẽ giúp câu ngắn gọn hơn, chủ động, và vào
the point.
trọng tâm hơn.
So we should use verbs to do the job of verbs!
Ta nên để động từ được làm công việc của chúng!